Register of the Albert C. Wedemeyer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1938-1988 (Boxes 5-23)
  - Speech, Little Big Horn commemoration ceremony, Hardin, Montana, mimeograph, 1951 June 25 (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - Speech, Declaration of Independence commemoration, Portland, Oregon, mimeograph, 1951 July 2 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - Speech, Los Angeles Rotary Club, Los Angeles, mimeograph, 1951 July 6 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Speech, Bohemian Club, Bohemian Grove, California, typescript and mimeographs, 1951 July 22 (Box-folder 9: 20)
  - Speech, speaking tour, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, 1951 July 31 (Box-folder 9: 21)
    Clippings, 1951.
  - "Factors in the Formulation of a National Strategy," lecture, National War College, 1951 August 28 (Box-folder 9: 22)
    Mimeograph and letter, 1951-1986.
  - "Korea Truce Will Not Last," U. S. News and World Report, 1951 September 14 (Box-folder 9: 23)
    Printed copy and letter, 1951.
  - Testimony, Senate Internal Security Committee, 1951 September 19 (Box-folder 9: 24)
    Transcript, typescript excerpt, clippings, and correspondence with Joseph Alsop, Raymond P. Ludden, Pat McCarran, Benjamin Mandel, James Webb, Robert Welch, Jr. and others, 1945-1952.
  - "Let's Draw the Line Now," Collier's, 1951 November 17 (Box-folder 9: 25)
    Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence, 1951.
  - Statement, typescript, 1951 December 19 (Box-folder 9: 26)
    Relates to Wedemeyer's resignation from the Army.
  - Statement, typescript, 1952 (Box-folder 9: 27)
    Relates to foreign aid.
  - Speech, National Retail Dry Goods Association, New York, mimeograph, 1952 January 10 (Box-folder 9: 28)
    Relates to foreign policy.
  - Speech, Junior Chamber of Commerce, Bridgeport, Connecticut, mimeograph, 1952 January 23 (Box-folder 9: 29)
  - "Wedemeyer Hits Bipartisan Foreign Policy, Containment," Evening World-Herald, Lincoln Day speech, Omaha, Nebraska, printed excerpts, 1952 February 13 (Box-folder 9: 30)
  - "The Red Cross in War and Peace," speech, Red Cross, Toledo, Ohio, mimeograph, 1952 February 19 (Box-folder 9: 31)
  - "Tomorrow May Be Too Late," mimeograph, 1952 February 17-23 (Box-folder 9: 32)
  - Speech, mimeograph, 1952 February 26 (Box-folder 9: 33)
    Relates to the Red Cross and foreign policy.
  - Speeches, speaking tour, Utah, mimeographs, 1952 February 28-29 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Speech, Land O'Lakes Convention, Minneapolis, mimeograph, 1952 March 13 (Box-folder 10: 2)
    Relates to communism and foreign policy.
  - Speech, Farm and Home Week Conference, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, mimeograph, 1952 March 19 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - "Concept for Employment of Military Forces in Future War,", 1952 April 18 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    Partial typescript and letter, 1968.
  - Television interview, WBZ-TV, New Bedford, Massachusetts, mimeograph transcript, 1952 April 28 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Press statement, mimeograph, 1952 July 11 (Box-folder 10: 6)
    Relates to the 1952 Republican presidential nomination.
  - Speech, lecture, Air War College, Maxwell Field, Alabama, mimeograph, 1952 October 1 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Speech, West Branch Manufacturers Association, Williamsport, Pennsylvania, mimeograph, 1952 October 14 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Speech, Citizens for Eisenhower-Nixon Committee dinner, New York, mimeograph, 1952 October 22 (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - "The Truth About Korea," radio and television broadcast, Los Angeles, 1952 November 2 (Box-folder 10: 10)
    Mimeograph, printed copies, and correspondence, 1952. See also: AUDIOVISUAL FILE.
  - Fragments and notes, 1952 December 5-8 (Box-folder 10: 11)
    Prepared for the AVCO Digest. Includes material relating to NATO, Europe, and Trygve Lie. Typescript fragments and memoranda, 1952.
  - Speech, New York State Agricultural Society, Albany, mimeograph, 1953 January 21 (Box-folder 10: 12)
  - Speech, Boys' Clubs of America, mimeograph, 1953 May 14 (Box-folder 10: 13)
    Relates to communism.
  - Speech, Bendix luncheon, EEI Annual Convention, Atlantic City, mimeograph, 1953 June 2 (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - Speech, Festival of Lithuania Art and Music, Washington, D.C., mimeograph, 1953 June 20 (Box-folder 10: 15)
  - Statement, 1953 July 23 (Box-folder 10: 16)
    Relates to Egypt. Letter and telegram, 1953.
  - Press conference, clipping, 1953 September 4 (Box-folder 10: 17)
  - Speeches, speaking tour, mimeographs, 1953 October 14-15 (Box-folder 10: 18)
  - Speech, Society of the Silurians, Washington, D.C., mimeograph, 1953 November 9 (Box-folder 10: 19)
  - Speech, National Editorial Association, Chandler, Arizona, mimeograph, 1954 January 15 (Box-folder 10: 20)
  - Speech, Board of Trade, Toronto, Canada, typescript, 1954 January 25 (Box-folder 10: 21)
    Relates to foreign relations.
  - Speech, Temple University, Philadelphia, mimeograph, 1954 February 18 (Box-folder 10: 22)
    Relates to communism and education.
  - Speech, Republican Executive Committee of Palm Beach County, Palm Beach, Florida, mimeograph, 1954 March 29 (Box-folder 10: 23)
    Relates to Adlai Stevenson and politics.
  - "Too Much to Ask," [Baltimore] News-Post-American, 1954 May 8 (Box-folder 10: 24)
    Clipping and letter, 1954.
  - "The Wedemeyer Plan," [Omaha] Morning World Herald, clipping, 1954 June 17 (Box-folder 10: 25)
    Report of congressional testimony.
  - Open letter (with others), New York Times, printed copy, 1955 February 28 (Box-folder 10: 26)
  - "Soviet Strategy," contribution to a House Committee on Un-American Affairs symposium, 1956 July (Box-folder 10: 27)
    Typescript and correspondence with Francis E. Walter, 1956.
  - "World War II Strategy and Its Significance Today,", 1956 August 29 (Box-folder 10: 28)
    Correspondence, 1956.
  - "Keep 'Em Out," One Man's Opinion, 1956 November (Box-folder 10: 29)
    Relates to the proposed admission of China to the United Nations. Typescript, printed copy, and letter by Robert H. W. Welch, Jr., 1956.
  - "Principles of Military Strategy," speech, NATO Defense College, typescripts and mimeograph, 1957 February 27 (Box-folder 10: 30)
  - "Observations on Trip in Europe," mimeograph and notes, 1957 February-March (Box-folder 10: 31)
  - "Strategy," lecture, National War College, 1957 March 15 (Box-folder 10: 32)
    Typescript and letters, 1957.
  - Radio broadcast, Manion Forum, 1957 May 25 (Box-folder 10: 33)
    Correspondence with Clarence Manion, clippings, flyer, and resolutions, 1957-1959.
  - Statement, 1957 June (Box-folder 10: 34)
    Prepared for the Omaha World Herald. Typescript and letter, 1957.
  - Letter to the editor (date written), Tablet, 1957 June 28 (Box-folder 10: 35)
    Typescript and clipping, 1957.
  - Speech, dedication of Lindbergh Plaque, Long Island, New York, 1957 July 24 (Box-folder 10: 36)
    Typescript, correspondence, and miscellany, 1957.
  - Statement, [Omaha] Evening World Herald, advertisement, printed copy, 1957 September 24 (Box-folder 10: 37)
  - Speech, Omaha Rotary Club?, typescript, 1958? (Box-folder 10: 38)
  - Wedemeyer Reports! (1958)
    - General, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 11: 1)
      Relates to a libel suit by Philip Fugh. Correspondence and statements by Allen Dulles, J. Edgar Hoover and others.
    - Background notes, circa 1941-1951 (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1952-1988
        Includes letters by Clarence Cannon, Philip Cortney, Walter Ditmars, H. Doerr, Victor Emanuel, Craig Hosmer, Francis Neilson, Jouett Shouse, Clyde Tolson and others.
        - 1958 (Box-folder 11: 3-4)
        - 1959-1988 (Box-folder 12: 1-5)
      - Publishing companies (primarily Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc.), 1951-1973 (Box-folder 13: 1-4)
      - Utley, Freda, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Draft fragments (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Excerpts, 1959 May (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Reviews, 1958-1971 (Box-folder 13: 8-9)
  - "The Communist Program for World Conquest," consultation, United States House of Representatives, Committee on Un-American Activities, 1958 January 21 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    Printed copy, reports, clippings and press reports, guide, and correspondence with Richard Arens, William F. Heimlich, and others, 1957-1958.
  - Speech, Rollins College, Winter Park, Florida, 1958 February 24 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    Typescript, clipping, correspondence, and miscellany, 1958.
  - "This Is Your Life," television appearance relating to Father Hubbard, 1958 April 30 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    Correspondence and script, 1958.
  - Statement, circa 1958 September (Box-folder 14: 4)
    Relates to Wedemeyer Reports! Typescript and letter, 1958.
  - "The Real Issue in the Formosa Straits Action," The Blessings of Liberty, printed copy, 1958 October (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Letter to the editor (date written), New York Times, 1958 October 2 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    Reply to letter to the editor by Henry Waldman. Relates to Taiwan. Typescript, letters, and printed copy of Waldman's letter, 1958.
  - Speeches, speaking tour, 1958 November (Box-folder 14: 7)
    Correspondence, clippings, and miscellany, 1958.
  - "Appeasement in China: Where it Leads," Human Events, printed copy, 1958 November 17 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Radio interview, mimeograph transcript, 1958 November 30 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Speech, Racquet Club, New York, typescript outline, 1958 December 11 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - "International Developments,", 1959 January 6-10 (Box-folder 14: 11)
    Correspondence and clippings, 1958-1959.
  - "The Red Cross in War and Peace,", 1959 January 27 (Box-folder 14: 12)
    Letters and typescripts, 1958-1959.
  - Speech, Rotary Club, Buffalo, New York, 1959 February 5 (Box-folder 14: 13)
    Correspondence and schedule, 1958-1959.
  - Speech, German Society of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, 1959 February 8 (Box-folder 14: 14)
    Correspondence, miscellany, and clipping, 1959.
  - Speech, book and author luncheon, Cleveland, Ohio, 1959 February 19 (Box-folder 14: 15)
  - Speech, Society of Cincinnati, New York, 1959 February 23 (Box-folder 14: 16)
    Typescript, correspondence, and schedule, 1958-1959.
  - Speech, Hamilton Street Club, Baltimore, Maryland, 1959 February 26 (Box-folder 14: 17)
    Correspondence, 1958-1959.
  - "American Politics Reevaluated in the Missile Age,", 1959 March 8 (Box-folder 14: 18)
    Correspondence, program, miscellany, and clippings, 1958-1959.
  - Speeches, speaking tour, 1959 March 10-14 (Box-folder 14: 19)
    Correspondence, clipping, and partial radio broadcast transcript, 1958-1959.
  - Speeches, speaking tour, New York state, 1959 April 6-20 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    Correspondence, clipping, and miscellany, 1959.
  - "The Challenge in International Relations," speech, Freedom Forum, Searcy, Arkansas, 1959 April 21 (Box-folder 15: 2)
    Mimeograph, correspondence, and printed material, 1958-1959.
  - Speeches, speaking tour, 1959 May (Box-folder 15: 3)
    Correspondence and clippings, 1959.
  - Radio broadcast, Manion Forum, typescript, 1959 May 6 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Speech, Central Christian College, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, 1959 June 4 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    Correspondence and clipping, 1959.
  - Speech, American Legion, Mitchell, South Dakota, 1959 June 24 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Review of military history articles, 1959 August (Box-folder 15: 7)
    Prepared for Collier's Encyclopedia by Patrick W. Powers under Wedemeyer's supervision. Typescript, and correspondence with Powers and others, 1959.
  - Speeches, speaking tour, California, 1959 September (Box-folder 15: 8)
    Holograph, typescript, clipping, correspondence, and miscellany, 1959.
  - Speech, book and author luncheon, San Francisco, 1959 September 23 (Box-folder 15: 9)
    Typescript and correspondence, 1959.
  - Speech, American Legion, New York, typescript, 1959 September 25 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Speech, McKay-Shields executive conference, Absecon, New Jersey, 1959 October 2 (Box-folder 15: 11)
    Correspondence, 1959.
  - "Unholy Bond Links China, Soviet Reds," San Diego Union, 1959 October 2 (Box-folder 15: 12)
    Printed copy and clipping, 1959.
  - Speech, State Nurses Association, New York, 1959 October 7 (Box-folder 15: 13)
    Correspondence and miscellany, 1959.
  - Speech, Mercersburg Academy, Mercersburg, Pennsylvania, 1959 October 17 (Box-folder 15: 14)
    Printed copy, correspondence, clippings, and miscellany, 1959.
  - Speech, Columbia Club, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1959 October 22 (Box-folder 15: 15)
    Relates to foreign policy. Typescript, serial issues, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence, 1959.
  - "International Developments in an Atomic Age,", 1959 October 27 (Box-folder 15: 16)
    Program and correspondence, 1959-1960.
  - Speech, Veterans Day, Arlington Cemetery, Arlington, Virginia, 1959 November 11 (Box-folder 15: 17)
    Typescript, miscellany, and correspondence, 1959.
  - "International Tensions in an Atomic Age," speech, All-American Conference to Combat Communism, Columbus, Ohio, 1959 November 13 (Box-folder 15: 18)
    Typescript, mimeograph, clipping, correspondence, and miscellany, 1959.
  - Speech, Karl Mundt recognition dinner, Aberdeen, South Dakota, 1959 December 8 (Box-folder 15: 19)
    Typescript, clipping, miscellany, and correspondence with Karl Mundt and others, 1959.
  - Miscellaneous drafts and notes, 1960-1969
    - General (Box-folder 15: 20)
      Primarily relates to foreign relations.
    - Southeast Asia (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - "International Developments in an Atomic Age," speech, Colonial Dames of America, Philadelphia, 1960 January 20 (Box-folder 16: 2)
    Typescript and correspondence, 1959-1960.
  - "Statement for the Press," announcement of withdrawal from congressional campaign, typescript, 1960 March (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Speech, Daughters of the American Revolution annual defense luncheon, Washington, D.C., typescript, 1960 March 10 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    Relates to foreign affairs.
  - Speech, University of Wichita, Wichita, Kansas, 1960 March 15 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    Relates to foreign policy. Typescript, clippings, and correspondence, 1959-1960.
  - "Human Values in the Space Age," speech, The Citadel, Charleston, South Carolina, 1960 April 2 (Box-folder 16: 6)
    Typescript, clippings, and correspondence, 1960.
  - "Strategy for Freedom,", 1960 April 15-18 (Box-folder 16: 7)
    Typescripts, clippings, correspondence, and miscellany, 1960.
  - "Tell Khrushchev We Are Ready for War, if Necessary," Manion Forum, radio broadcast, 1960 May 1 (Box-folder 16: 8)
    Typescripts, printed transcript, clippings, printed material, and correspondence with Clarence Manion, Walter Robertson, and others, 1960.
  - Speech, book and author luncheon, Frederick, Maryland, 1960 May 3 (Box-folder 16: 9)
    Correspondence, 1960.
  - Radio broadcast, typescript, 1960 May 20 (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - "Wedemeyer Accuses Monty of Following Red China Line," New York World-Telegram and Sun, 1960 June 22 (Box-folder 16: 11)
    Letter to the editor relating to comments by Field Marshal Montgomery. Typescript, printed copies, and correspondence with Strom Thurmond, Robert Welch and others, 1960.
  - "Patriotism, 1960," television broadcast, WNAC-TV, Boston, 1960 August 2 (Box-folder 16: 12)
    Interview questions, correspondence, and miscellany, 1960.
  - Speech, Republican fundraising dinner, Tekamah, Nebraska, 1960 September 8 (Box-folder 16: 13)
    Typescript, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence with Carl Curtis and others, 1960.
  - "Foundation Stones of Character," speech, Presbyterian Church, Darnestown, Maryland, typescript, 1960 October 16 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Speech, Mary Baldwin College, Staunton, Virginia, 1960 October 22 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    Typescript fragments, correspondence, and miscellany, 1960-1961.
  - "Character: The Bulwark Against Communism," speech, Episcopal Church of Our Saviour, Washington, D.C., 1960 December 4 (Box-folder 17: 2)
    Typescript, correspondence, and miscellany, 1960.
  - Speech, Kiwanis Club, Denver, Colorado, 1961 February 15 (Box-folder 17: 3)
    Relates to foreign policy. Typescript, correspondence, clipping, and miscellany, 1961.
  - "The Soviet Challenge to American Education," speech, American Economic Foundation, Houston, 1961 March 8 (Box-folder 17: 4)
    Typescript, program, clippings and correspondence, 1961.
  - "Khrushchev's Challenge to American Education," speech, American Economic Foundation, Philadelphia, 1961 March 27 (Box-folder 17: 5)
    Typescript, program, clippings, and correspondence, 1960-1961.
  - "International Powder Kegs," speaking tour, 1961 April 17-19 (Box-folder 17: 6)
    Typescript, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence, 1961.
  - "Strategy for Peace," speech, American Petroleum Institute, Los Angeles, California, 1961 May 11 (Box-folder 17: 7)
    Typescript, correspondence, and miscellany, 1961.
  - Speech, Chevy Chase Women's Republican Club, Chevy Chase, Maryland, 1961 May 30 (Box-folder 17: 8)
    Clipping and correspondence, 1961.
  - Speech, American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, Los Angeles, California, typescript, 1961 June 3 (Box-folder 17: 9)
    Relates to U. S. foreign relations with Taiwan and the People's Republic of China.
  - Speech, American Security Council, Salt Lake City, Utah, 1961 June 5 (Box-folder 17: 10)
    Typescript, flyer, and correspondence, 1961.
  - "The Physical Defense of Freedom," speech, Conference on the Necessary Conditions of a Free Society, 1961 June 12-17 (Box-folder 17: 11)
    Typescript, mimeograph, program, mimeograph copies of T. Robert Ingram, "Christianity and Freedom," Felix Morley, "Political Conditions for a Free Society," and Eliseo Vivas, "Freedom: The Philosophical Problem," typescript introduction by Morley to the published essay collection, and correspondence with Arthur Kemp, Hal Luhnow, Morley, and others, 1961-1974.
  - "International Developments in an Atomic Age," speech, Volksfest Association, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1961 June 18 (Box-folder 17: 12)
    Typescript, clippings, correspondence, and miscellany, 1961.
  - "Survival Is Not Enough," Elks Magazine, 1961 July (Box-folder 17: 13)
    Typescript, printed copies, miscellany, and correspondence with Bruno Shaw, Robert E. Wood and others, 1961.
  - Letter to the editor (date written), Houston Chronicle, 1961 August 8 (Box-folder 17: 14)
    Relates to the Connally Amendment and the World Court. Typescript, clipping, and correspondence, 1971.
  - Speech, Americanism seminar, San Antonio, Texas, 1961 September 23 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    Typescript, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence with H. L. Hunt, Samuel T. Williams and others, 1961.
  - "International Powder Kegs," speech, Austin Anti-Communist League, Austin, Texas, 1961 October 23 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    Typescripts, correspondence, clippings, and miscellany, 1961.
  - Speech, Life Line Freedom Seminar, Amarillo, Texas, 1961 November 7 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    Typescript fragment, correspondence, clippings, and miscellany, 1961.
  - Speech, Junior Chamber of Commerce, Washington, D.C., 1961 December 14 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    Relates to U.S. foreign policy in Europe. Typescript outline, clippings, and background material, 1961.
  - "International Developments in an Atomic Age," speech, YMCA, Omaha, Nebraska, 1962 January 17 (Box-folder 18: 5)
    Typescript, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence with Howard Buffett and others, 1961-1962.
  - "International Developments in an Atomic Age," speech, Boys' Club, Dothan, Alabama, 1962 February 26 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    Typescripts, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence, 1961-1962.
  - Statement, prepared for the La Salle County [Illinois] Historical Society, typescript, 1962 April 6 (Box-folder 18: 7)
    Relates to W. H. L. Wallace.
  - "Cuba: A Conservative Critique," Town Hall radio broadcast, 1963 May 7 (Box-folder 18: 8)
    Notes, list of questions, miscellany, and correspondence, 1963.
  - "Military Leaders Denounce Article Alleging Blunders," San Diego Union, 1963 June 23 (Box-folder 18: 9)
    Reply to an article by Jack Anderson. Typescript, printed copy, letter, and clipping, 1963.
  - Speeches, otherwise unidentified speeches in support of Barry Goldwater, typescript and clippings, 1964 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Speech, Fu Jen Catholic University, New York, New York, 1964 February 1 (Box-folder 18: 11)
    Typescripts, clippings, mimeograph (German translation), miscellany, background material relating to the university, and correspondence with M. J. Broucek, Karel F. Stekr and another, 1964-1965.
  - Discussion, Cresap Association, Frederick, Maryland, 1964 February 10 (Box-folder 18: 12)
    Typescript outline, printed material, and correspondence, 1963-1964.
  - Speeches, speaking tour, California, 1964 April 20-26 (Box-folder 18: 13)
    Typescript, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence, 1964.
  - Speeches, West Coast speaking tour, 1964 May 12-14 (Box-folder 18: 14)
    Relates to Barry Goldwater's presidential candidacy. Typescripts, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence, 1964.
  - Speech, Rotary Club, Rockville, Maryland, typescript outline, 1964 May 28 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    Relates to China and World War II.
  - Television broadcast, Goldwater rally, Buena Park, California, 1964 May 30 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    Typescripts, television script, clippings, notes, miscellany, and correspondence with Robert W. Berry, John Ford, Robert McClure, John Wayne and others, 1964.
  - Speech, Junior Chamber of Commerce, Gaithersburg, Maryland, 1964 June 27 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    Typescript outline and certificate, 1964.
  - "Barry Goldwater: Mr. American, 1964,", 1964 July 7 (Box-folder 19: 4)
    Typescripts, mimeograph, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence with Robert Anderson and others, 1964.
  - Speech, address to the Republican National Convention, typescript, 1964 July 11 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - Introduction for Barry Goldwater, Bohemian Grove, California, 1964 August 1 (Box-folder 19: 6)
    Typescripts, correspondence, and clippings, 1964.
  - Speech, Colorado Republican Leaders, Denver, typescript, 1964 August 6 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    Relates to Barry Goldwater.
  - "A General's Hope," San Diego Union, printed copy, 1964 August 13 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Interview, [London] Sunday Times, 1964 September (Box-folder 19: 9)
    Typescript excerpts, and correspondence with Godfrey Smith, 1964.
  - Speech, Republican fundraising dinner, Fremont, Nebraska, 1964 September 4 (Box-folder 19: 10)
    Typescript, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence with Roman Hruska and others, 1964.
  - Speech, Republican rally, Yakima, Washington, 1964 September 20 (Box-folder 19: 11)
    Typescripts, miscellany, clippings, and correspondence, 1964.
  - Speeches, speaking tour, 1964 September (Box-folder 19: 12)
    Letter, clipping, and miscellany, 1964.
  - Speech, Republican dinner, Greenwich, Connecticut, 1964 October 1 (Box-folder 19: 13)
    Typescript and letters, 1964.
  - Comments on J. Evetts Haley, A Texan Looks at Lyndon, and John Stormer, None Dare Call it Treason, typescripts and letter, 1964 October 6 (Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Speech, Republican rally, Jacksonville, Florida, 1964 October 6 (Box-folder 19: 15)
    Typescripts, clippings, miscellany, and correspondence, 1964.
  - Speech, Republican rally, Winchester, Virginia, 1964 October 10 (Box-folder 19: 16)
    Typescript, miscellany, and letters, 1964.
  - "President Chiang Kai-shek as I Know Him,", 1964 October 15 (Box-folder 19: 17)
    Typescript and correspondence with Tsao Sheng-fen, 1964.
  - Speeches, speaking tour, Goldwater campaign, 1964 October 19-30 (Box-folder 19: 18)
    Typescripts, correspondence, miscellany, and clippings, 1964.
  - Speech, Rotary Club, Bethesda, Maryland, 1964 November 17 (Box-folder 20: 1)
    Typescript outline and correspondence, 1964.
  - Speech, Virginia Military Institute, Lexington, Virginia, 1964 December 5 (Box-folder 20: 2)